Guide to the REPOhistory Archive MSS.113
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VIII: Artwork
  - Subseries B: Lower Manhattan Sign Project
    - Sign 21: Our blankets for your beaver (2 copies), 1992; cuid6251; 2 items two signs (Folder VIII, 22, Object MSS.113.cuid6251a-b)
    - Sign 22: You are standing on landfill (2 copies), 1992; cuid6252; 2 items two signs (Folder VIII, 23, Object MSS.113.cuid6252a-b)
    - Sign 23A: "The evilest woman in New York!," screamed the headlines when Ann Lohman, alias Madame Restell, was arrested in 1878. (3 copies), 1992; cuid6253; 3 items three signs (Folder 24, Object MSS.113.cuid6253a-c)
    - Sign 23B: Anthony J. Comstock (1844-1915), the nemesis of Madame Restell (see nearby sign), devoted most of his adult life to a crusade against obscenity which he defined to include birth control and abortion (2 copies), 1992; cuid6268; 2 items two signs (Item MSS.113.cuid6268a-b)
    - Sign 24: Office workers eat their lunch (3 copies), 1992; cuid6254; 3 items three signs (Folder 25, Object MSS.113.cuid6254a-c)
    - Sign 25: Sticks and stones may break her bones but names…? (2 copies), 1992; cuid6255; 2 items two signs (Folder 26, Object MSS.113.cuid6255a-b)
    - Sign 26: Welcome to Gotham City (3 copies), 1992; cuid6256; 3 items three signs (Folder 27, Object MSS.113.cuid6256a-c)
    - Sign 27: Public School Cholera Hospital (2 copies), 1992; cuid6257; 2 items two signs (Folder 28, Object MSS.113.cuid6257a-b)
    - Sign 28: Frances Wright (3 copies), 1992; cuid6258; 3 items three signs (Folder 29, Object MSS.113.cuid6258a-c)
    - Sign 29: Vito Marcantonio: The People's Congressman, 1992; cuid6259; 1 item one sign (Folder 30, Object MSS.113.cuid6259)
    - Sign 30: Nonviolent Protests Against Civil Defense Drills in NYC (3 copies), 1992; cuid6260; 3 items three signs (Folder 31, Object MSS.113.cuid6260a-c)
    - Sign 31: Fight Tonight, 1992; cuid6261; 1 item one sign (Folder 32, Object MSS.113.cuid6261)
    - Sign 32: Forlorn house (3 copies), 1992; cuid6262; 3 items three signs (Folder 33, Object MSS.113.cuid6262a-c)
    - Sign 33: No Where to Go, 1992; cuid6263; 1 item one sign (Folder 34, Object MSS.113.cuid6263)
    - Sign 34: "It was a desolate, unappropriated spot…" (2 copies), 1992; cuid6264; 2 items two signs (Folder 35, Object MSS.113.cuid6264a-b)
    - Sign 36: United Tailoresses' Society of New York, 1992; cuid6265; 1 item one sign (Folder 36, Object MSS.113.cuid6265)
  - Subseries C: Buttermilk Bottom
    All signs are printed on the front and back. In cases in which text appears on both sides it is noted in the transcription, otherwise the text appears only on the back. Each sign features the following text on the bottom of the back side with the REPOhistory logo and the Arts Festival of Atlanta logo on the left and right, respectively, of the first line: Entering Buttermilk Bottom. Despite harsh conditions imposed by segregation, Buttermilk Bottom was a vibrant community with African-American-run schools, churches and businesses. Its bulldozing under "urban renewal" during the 1960's damaged community structures throughout Atlanta.
    - Sign 1: Entering Buttermilk Bottom (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6207; 2 items two signs (Folder 37, Object MSS.113.cuid6207a-b)
    - Sign 2: Urban Renewal, 1995-1996; cuid6208; 1 item one sign (Folder 38, Object MSS.113.cuid6208)
    - Sign 3: Welcome to the Double Shotguns, 1995-1996; cuid6209; 1 item one sign (Folder 39, Object MSS.113.cuid6209)
    - Sign 4: What is the effect of urban renewal on crime? (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6210; 2 items two signs (Folder 40, Object MSS.113.cuid6210a-b)
    - Sign 5: Most hard-working men and women of that day usually sang... [Woodman / Coldman](2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6211; 2 items two signs (Folder 41, Object MSS.113.cuid6211a-b)
    - Sign 6: Wash Lady, Scrub Lady, 1995-1996; cuid6212; 1 item one sign (Folder 42, Object MSS.113.cuid6212)
    - Sign 7: House on Fire, 1995-1996; cuid6213; 1 item one sign (Folder 43, Object MSS.113.cuid6213)
    - Sign 8: Mrs. Sara Lena Echols Malone raised her family on 267 Pine Place Apt. #3 in the early thirties., 1995-1996; cuid6214; 1 item one sign (Folder 44, Object MSS.113.cuid6214)
    - Sign 9: …I sing because I'm happy (3 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6215; 3 items three signs (Folder 45, Object MSS.113.cuid6215a-c)
    - Sign 10: War is Hell, 1995-1996; cuid6216; 1 item one sign (Folder 46, Object MSS.113.cuid6216)
    - Sign 11: Nearly every corner in Buttermilk Bottom boasted a beauty salon, shoe repair shop or restaurant, many owned by African-Americans, 1995-1996; cuid6217; 1 item one sign (Folder 47, Object MSS.113.cuid6217)
    - Sign 12: Renewal (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6218; 2 items two signs (Folder 48, Object MSS.113.cuid6218a-b)
    - Sign 13: "…we have caught the sunshine in the bricks and mortar of our homes and have builded therein not one ignoble prejudice or memory." (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6219; 2 items two signs (Folder 49, Object MSS.113.cuid6219a-b)
    - Sign 14: Do you know where your neighborhood is?, 1995-1996; cuid6220; 1 item one sign (Folder 50, Object MSS.113.cuid6220)
    - Sign 15: Alleyway on Felton, 1995-1996; cuid6221; 1 item one sign (Folder 51, Object MSS.113.cuid6221)
    - Sign 16: Remember in this valley there was a neighborhood torn down, 1995-1996; cuid6222; 1 item one sign (Folder 52, Object MSS.113.cuid6222)
    - Sign 17: Segregation on the map (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6223; 2 items two signs (Folder 53, Object MSS.113.cuid6223a-b)
    - Sign 18: Welcome to Buttermilk Bottom (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6224; 2 items two signs (Folder 54, Object MSS.113.cuid6224a-b)
    - Sign 19: Penny Candy (2 copies), 1995-1996; cuid6225; 2 items two signs (Folder 55, Object MSS.113.cuid6225a-b)
    - Sign 20: [Untitled], 1995-1996; cuid6226; 1 item one sign (Folder 56, Object MSS.113.cuid6226)
    - Sign: Entering Buttermilk Bottom, large, Undated; cuid6227; 1 item one sign (Folder 75, Object MSS.113.cuid6227)
      Direction signs.
  - Subseries D: Civil Disturbances
    - [Bruno v. Codd - 1978 Legal victory for battered women] Civil Disturbances Sign #1, 1998-1999; cuid6269; 1 item one sign (Folder 57, Object MSS.113.cuid6269)
  - Subseries E: Circulations, Undated
    - St. Cloud State University sign [Racism interrupts], Undated; cuid6228; 1 item one sign (Folder 73, Object MSS.113.cuid6228)
- Series IX: Ephemera
  - T-shirts - Hudson Valley Middle School (Box 77)
    [removed from Series II, Subseries I, Box 9, Folder 10]
  - Plaster casts of pills (Box 20)
  - Vinyl strips with red dots (Box 20)
- Accretion 2012 - Series VIII: Artwork
  - Metal mounts for signs from the Lower Manhattan Sign Project, undated (Box 21)
    Provenance
    These mounts were acquired in 2012 from Cooper Union, who exhibited 5 signs in the exhibition, "Ruptures: Forms of Public Address" (9/4/12 - 10/13/12) at 41 Cooper Gallery.